Chukwudalu Josemaria Ayika

Assembly close, Folagoro, Shomolu, Lagos State, Nigeria. +2348068537341 chukwudaluay@gmail.com

BIODATA

Sex: Male

Marital Status: Single

Date of birth: 28th December 1993

State Of Origin: Anambra

SUMMARY

Intermediate Frontend developer with 3+ years of experience building responsive websites and applications with extensive knowledge of Javascript and Javascript frameworks; committed to building clean and highly functional user interfaces for personal and business purposes and communicating with backend APIs using technologies built upon Javascript and Typescript languages while following industry best practices and contributing towards making a great impact with commitment, hard work, and research while building my admirable career.

Most of the previous projects I worked on were developed using JavaScript (Vanilla), Typescript, React, Next.js, Vue.js, Nuxt.js and Angular.

I can be a great team player if/when the ecosystem encourages it.

EXPERIENCE

Full-stack Software Engineer [Vue] Kinfolk Venture Capital

August 2022 - Date

- Train new frontend developers to help them get acquainted with the current architecture
- Offers private mentorship program to guide new frontend developers
- Track Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) for potential portfolio companies in line with the UN.

Frontend Engineer [Vue] Kinfolk Venture Capital

Oct 2021 - Date

- Integral part of a multi-functional team building and maintaining the user and admin facing views of the Onyx app built with Vue
- Re-build and maintain the company's website (Kinfolk)
- Solo project work on the Kinfolk Blog app built with Nuxt.js on the frontend and set up with wordpress as a CMS
- Provided <u>website</u> with multi-lingual support by integrating I18n international language translation software with our application.
- Collect, organize and document KPIs for startups making progress towards Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs)

Frontend Developer (Contract/Remote) [React] Campbell.ng

October 2021 - November 2021

- Built campbell.ng web app with React and Redux
- Rendered media in web friendly formats such as .webp and lottie to optimize app loading speeds by up to 27%.

Frontend Engineer [Angular] Quabbly Inc.

May 2021 – October 2021

- Part of a team which consisted of frontend engineers, backend engineers and UI/UX designers working on the <u>Quabbly App</u>. My role included working closely with designers and backend to convert UI prototypes and consume backend endpoints to create functional and user-friendly interfaces for end-users on the app.
- Gained valuable experience working where it is unacceptable for non-production-ready code to be pushed to the repository, thereby spurring me to compile bits of test-driven production-ready code to create components.
- Actively worked in an Agile development environment building no-code solutions.
- Quabbly is a web-app that helps you organize your life, from documents, private and public, collect data via Quabbly forms on Quabbly's website etc. which was the last project I took on, I appreciate the effort put into this project by my team Alex Abiola (UI/UX), Adunola Odetola (FE)
- Working in a multidisciplinary team with amazing professionals, backend engineers and designers helped me in developing a vast knowledge on software creation.

Frontend Engineer (Contract/Remote) [React] TotalHealthCare

April 2021 – July 2021

- Realigned and optimized the User Interface of the product built with React and Redux.
- Suggested redesigning of user interface which boosted user visits by about 13%.
- Built new flexible and reusable components which streamlined the flow of data according to best practices.
- Optimized queries between the backend and frontend to send and receive data from users.

Frontend Developer (Remote) [React] Stutern

June 2019 - Jan 2020

- Worked closely with UI/UX in coming up with functional and user-friendly prototypes for developers.
- Proficient in HTML, CSS, SaaS, JavaScript, React, Gatsby and make use of these technologies appropriately in order to create cross-platform and user-friendly web pages.
- Conducted user research and testing to get accurate feedback from users.

Head of Social Media

National Youth Service Corps (Ikeja, Lagos state) July 2016 – September 2018

EDUCATION

Stutern Graduate Accelerator Program (Front End Engineering) • 2019 Bachelors in Business Administration.

Ecole Supérieure d'Enseignement Professionnel. • Cotonou, Benin Republic. • 2016

West African Senior School Certificate (WASSCE) Christ the King College. • Odolewu, Ijebu-ode, Ogun State, Nigeria. • 2011

CERTIFICATIONS

LinkedIn Learning Licenses & Certifications

LinkedIn courses and certified on HTML, CSS and JavaScript, React/ReactJs (Issued June 2020)

Front End Engineering track, Stutern (SGA 06 Cohort)

SKILLS

Creative Coding

CSS/Sass

React

Vue.js

Angular

Next.js

Nuxt.js

Gatsby.js

Social Media Management

Problem solving

REFERENCES

Available on request